Finding Aid for the The Fuson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
The Andrew Nelson Lytle 1988 Addition
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0161
1.68 linear_feet
- Correspondence-outgoing--April, 1949 - April 1960
  - Professor E.R. Pinkson, U.S. Naval Academy, 4/49
  - Dr. R. T. Abercrombie, Johns Hopkins Club, 4/49
  - Mr. Barbour, 2/54
  - Ralph and Marian Harlow, 2/56
  - Dennis Hudson and Barbara Johnson, 3/60
  - Rev. Kelly Miller Smith, 3/60
  - Mrs. H. c. Darnell and Rev. and Mrs. c. G. Fuson, 3/60
  - Dr. Madison Sarratt, Mayor's Committee on Human Relations, 3/60
  - Dr. and Mrs. Looby, 4/60
  - Rev. James Bevel, Student Non-Violent Movement, 4/60
  - Pegg, 4/60
- Correspondence-Outgoing--June 1960 - Januarv 1970
  - Chancellor Harrie Branscomb, Vanderbilt University, 6/60
  - E. Mack Cates, 6/60
  - H. c. Nottebart, 7/60
  - R. L. Prescott, 7/60
  - John Sloan, 7/60
  - c. H. Handley, 7/60
  - Fred Harvey, Jr., 7/60
  - Joe Zahalka, 7/60
  - Norbert W. Smith, Bus Caravan from Detroit, 7/60
  - Katherine Jones, 6/61
  - Dan Fuson to catherine in jail, 6/61
  - Allan Fuson to Pauline in jail, 6/61
  - Matthew Walker, Jr., 6/61
  - John and Bernard, 6/61
  - students in jail, 6/61
  - Governor Ellington with Petition for Reinstatment of, 8/61
  - Students at TN A & I State U. (7/61), 8/61
  - Bernard Lafayette, Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, 8/62
  - Mr. Zimmerman, 2/63
  - National Conference of Friends on Race Relations, 5/68
  - Avon Williams, 5/70
- Correspondence-Incoming--October, 1946-June 1960
  - Gloria Washington, 10/46
  - Miriam B. Ryan, 10/46
  - Earl R. Pinkson, 3/49
  - Nicholas Hobbs, Peabody College, 3/54
  - Sue and Dave Minter and Lindsey and Gene Cox, 5/55
  - Glenn E. Smiley, 11/55
  - Lindsey Cox, 11/55
  - Ralph Harlow, 1/56
  - Roger Shinn (Attached to Letter to Ralph Harlow), 1/56
  - Dennis Hudson, 3/60
  - Kelly Miller Smith, NCLC, 11/55
  - David N. Wiley, 11/55
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, 4/60
  - Diane Nash and Peggy Alexander, 4/60
  - Marilyn Johnson, 4/60
  - Dr. J. Robert Nelson, 6/60
  - Dolores Crump, 6/60
- correspondence-Incoming--March, 1961-June 1974
  - Diane Nash, 3/61
  - T.L. Shuttlesworth, 5/61
  - Dick Shroeder, 5/61
  - Pauline to Allan Fuson, 6/61
  - catherine Burks to Danny Fuson, 6/61
  - Glen otis Martin, 8/61
  - Roy Williams of Wilson Quick, 2/62
  - cornell Hewson, 1/63
  - Bill Chambless, 2/63
  - Martha Ragland, 1/65
  - susan Wilsthire, 1/71
  - Susan Wiltshire, 4/71
  - Martha Ragland, 1/72
  - Mrs. Jessie Carney Smith, 8/73
  - A. D. Gill, Gulf Oil Corporation with Article "The Changing Face of Gulf in Nigeria, 6/74
- General Correspondence, 1956-1969
  - Letter to Ralph Harlow from Roger L. Shinn, 2/56
  - Letter to Friends from Dorie Ladner, 12/62
  - Letter to Mr. T. M. King from I. E. Otey, 3/69
  - Letter to Avon Williams from Mrs. Le o Burson, 10/69
- Writings by Nelson Fuson Bill to Reorganize the Local Courts
  - Letter to the Editor The Tennessean, 7/61
  - Note: Malcolm X Record Club
  - Note: student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee
  - Notes on panel discussion on Non- Violence
  - List of Recommended Books on Negros
- Personal Notes
  - Addresses
  - Letters-handwritten
  - Work Projects list
  - Selma to Montgomery March
- Writings by Others-Martha Raqland
  - Newsletter of the Tennessee Council on Human Relations, 9/66
  - Letter to the Editor, 11/66
  - Letter to Mayor Beverly Briley, 11/66
  - "Motivations and Methods of White Power", 7/67
  - Letter to Robert c. Weaver, Sect. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development, 12/67
  - "The Democratic Party in _Tennessee"Writings by Others-Edwin Mitchell, 2/71
  - Lecture No. 7 "New Directions in Human Relations", 3/68
  - Sermon delivered at Lenten Service of Christ Church Episcopal, 4/68
  - Letter to Alexander Looby Notes taken on speech delivered by Robert Bonthius, 2/69
  - Letter to William Mason Political Career-Avon Williams, 12/70
  - Political Advertisement, 8/68
  - Newspaper clipping, "State Senate District 19"1968 Questionnaire for Candidates to Tennessee General Assembly, 1968
  - Notes of Meeting to Honor Atty. Avon Williams Academic Career-Howard and Fisk Universities 1949-1954, 2/71
  - Newsletter of the Social Order Committees of the Philadelphia Yearly Meetings of the Society of Friends, 4/49
  - Letter to Clerks of Monthly Meetings from J. Harold Passmore, 4/49
  - Sigma Xi Club Lecture, Howard University Report of the President's Committee on Civil Rights, 5/49
  - Brotherhood Pledge campaign, 1/50
  - Speaker Outline: "The Double standard" NAACP, 4/53
  - Notice of Mass Meeting of NAACP with program including Kelly Miller Smith, 5/53
  - Letter to Friends from Nancy and Jim st. John, 1/54
  - Letter to Guy Taylor from Ned Bollinger of General Board of Education, Methodist Church, 1/54
  - Letter to Albert Wertham from Ned Bollinger, 1/54
  - Letter to James c. Barbour from Ned Bollinger, 1/54
  - Letter to James c. Barbour from Ingram Bloch, 2/54
  - Letter to Colleague from Fisk Campus Committee, NAACP, 2/54
  - Letter from Robert Rempfer for United Negro College Fund, 2/54
  - Letter from Pastor of Gordon Methodist Church to Friends with petition regarding Negro Youth in Nashville Youth Symphony Orchestra, 3/54
  - Events-lOth Annual Race Relations Institute-Fisk University (File 8)
  - Program about Thurgood Marshall, 7/53
  - Selected Bibliography, 7/53
- Selected Pamphlets and Periodicals (File 2)
- Events-11th Annual Race Relations Institute-Fisk University, 1954; Speech Delivered by Charles S. Jo}:lnson "The Future is Here" Events-Lawson Case-Vanderbilt University
- Events-Lawson Case-Vanderbilt University
  - Letter from Lorrain Giddings to Fusons Statement from the General Cabinet of the Student Christian Association, 1960
  - The Lawson-Vanderbilt Affair: Letters to Dean Nelson, 8/60
- Events-Work Camp Eigtheenth Avenue Community Center 3/61 Schedule
  - List: Outdoor Improvement Needs for Nursery School List of participants Menus, grocery list List of Work Camp Possibilities Letter promoting the Work Camp"It Can Happen Here" Summary of Work Camp experience Events-Fisk Institute
  - Names and addresses of participants in Ultraviolet-Visible Session Names and addresses of participants in the GLC Institute, 1967
  - Events-Fisk Institute
  - Names and addresses of participants in Ultraviolet-Visible Session, Names and addresses of participants in the GLC Institute; 1967
- Events-26th Annual Race Relations Institute-Fisk University
  - Handwritten notes, 7/69 (File 1)
  - (File 2)
    List: United Church Board for Homeland Ministries
    Address: "Black Separatism and Race Relations: Implications and Prospects" by Herman H. Long
    Address: Robert L. Terrell, Morehouse College
  - (File 3)
    Signatures of attendees
    Draft for outline
    Notes
    Program Schedule
- Events-Martin Luther King Holiday Celebration
  - "Join the King March" Program, Legislastive Plaza, 1/19/87 Notice:
- Events-Planninq Information for Student Leadership Conference and 30th Anniversary Sit-in Reunion
  - Minutes of meeting, 10/14/89
  - Minutes of meeting, 11/18/89
  - Agenda of meeting, 11/18/89
  - Minutes of Workshop Committee, 12/2/89
  - Minutes of Planning Committee, 1/13/90
  - Minutes of Planning Committee, 1/20/90
  - Handwritten notes? minutes, 1/27/90
  - Press Release, 1/31/90
- Events-Student Leadership Confererence and 30th Anniversitv Sit- in Reunion
  - Thirty Years Registration Certificates of Appreciation to Marian and Nelson Fuson, 2/90
  - Agenda of meeting, 2/3/90
  - Agenda of meeting, 2/10/90
  - Agenda of meeting, 2/17/90
  - Schedule, 2/22-24/90
- Organizations and Community Activities-Communitv Conference on Employment Opportunity (CCEO)
  - Mailing List, 3/60-10/60
  - Letter to Fusons from Wallace T. Dooley and Kelly Miller Smith, with Resolution in Support of the Conference, 3/60
  - Origin of the Conference 5/60 Elected Officers, 4/60
  - Report: "Employment Opportunity for Nashville Negroes" by Vivian W. Henderson, 9/60
  - Minutes of Gereral Meeting, 10/27/60
  - Agenda, 10/27/90
  - Minutes of Executive Committee Prospectus for 1961 Conference on Equal Employment Opportunity, 10/24/60
- Organizations and Community Activities-CCEO General Correspondence
  - CCEO Meeting Reminder, 10/60
  - NAACP Letter to Lyndon B. Johnson, 4/61
  - Letter to Nashville Surgical Supply Company from N. Fuson with response from Roy Williams of Wilson Quick, 2/62
  - Program: "A Human Relations Audit" sponsored by the Social Action Committee, 1/63
  - Report on CCEO by N. Fuson, 1/63
  - Minutes Handwritten Notes, 1/63
  - Listing of Possible Projects and Targets for Action
- Organizations and Community Activities-CCEO Commission on Industrial Firms (File 1)
  - 3/61-6/61
    List of Names, addresses, telephone numbers
  - Planning Meeting, 3/61
  - Minutes of Executive Committee Letter from Eli Cohen, National Committee on Employment of Youth, 3/61
  - Letter to N. Fuson from Wallace T. Dooley, 4/14/61
  - Letter to N. Fuson from Wallace T. Dooley, 4/17/61
  - Gentle Reminder, 4/29/61
  - Registration form Report of Visitation Committee, 4/22/61
  - Letter from Commission to Henry Ford, 5/61
  - Letter from N. Fuson to Byron L. Clark of AVCO General handwritten notes, 9/61
  - Memo, 6/61
  - Letter from Doris P. Dennison to Myron B. Towns 6/61 Memos, 6/61
  - Letter to F. Donald Hart from N. Fuson File 2 7/61-1/63, 6/61
  - Memo to subcommittee visiting Genesco, 7/61
  - Report of subcommittee on Industrial Firms: DuPont Company Summary of Preliminary Meetings of the CCEO Commission on Industrial Firms, 7/61
  - Handwritten interview with Ford Motor Company Glass Plant, 8/61
  - Progress Report on Negro Employment Opportunity in Nashville with Recommendations, 10/61
  - Typed interview with Western Electric, 11/61
  - Memo Re: the AVCO Situation, 12/61
  - Memo to N. Fuson from Gideon Fryer, NCRC, 1/62
  - Memo Re: Phone call to B. L. Clark, AVCO, 1/62
  - Memo to Tarleton, Miller and Elliott Re: Conference with Williams of Wilson Quick, 3/62
  - Letter to Wallace T. Dooley, Meharry from Sherman N.Webster, Social Action Committee, 1/63
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Christian Leadership Council (NCLC) 1960-1963 Executive Committee
  - List of NCLC Officers, 12/60
  - Minutes of Executive Committtee, 6/61
  - Letter to Bert Bigelow from Fusons with Response 9/61 Minutes of Meeting, 9/61
  - Letter to N. Fuson from Kelly Miller Smith 11/63 Letter to N. Fuson from Andrew White, 9/61
- Organizations and Community Activtities-Nashville Christian Leadership Council (NCLC) 1962-1963 Budget and Financial Campaign
  - Flyer: "Without Your Help Our Hands are Chained", 1962
  - "Toward the Beloved Community: Story of the NCLC, 1/62
  - General Agreements with NAACP Minutes of Meeting, 3/62
  - Letter to Fusons from Matthew Walker, 3/62
  - General Letter from N. Fuson, 3/62
  - Letter to N. Fuson from Kelly Miller Smith, 4/62
  - Newsletter: Support Operation Open City, 5/62
  - Letter to Fusons from Bernard Lafayette 1963 Paper: "This is NCLC", 8/62
  - Letter to James E. Parkin from Nelson Fuson, 5/63
  - Letter to N. Fuson from H.E. Braden and Andrew White, 9/63
  - Minutes Financial Campaign Meeting Project Committee Progress Report, 12/63
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Christian Leadership Council (NCLC), 1961-1964
  Financial Reports-File 2
  - Summary Financial Statement, 4/61
  - Summary Financial Statement, 5/61
  - Summary Financial Statement, 6/61
  - Summary Financial Statement, 7/61
  - Summary Financial Statement, 8/61
  - Letter to Friend from Kelly Miller Smith, 2/62
  - Letter to whom it may concern from Matthew Walker, 3/62
  - Financial Satements Jan.-April, 4/63
  - Budgeted Expenditures 9/64, 1963 10/63-
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Christian Leadership Council (NCLC) 1961
  - General Correspondence (Folder 1)
  - Letter from Student Non-Violent Movement Central Committee, 2/61
  - Letter to Citizens of Nashville from Nashville Student Non- Violent Movement, 2/61
  - Petition for Reinstatement of Students at Tennesee A & I, 7/61
  - Letter to Salynn McCollum from N. Fuson, 7/61
  - Suggested draft of NCLC letter to Salynn McCollum, 7/61
  - Letter to NCLC Financial Aid Committee from Salynn McCollum, 7/61
  - Letter to Financial Aid Committee from Salynn McCollum, 7/61
  - Letter from Mrs. W. C. McCollum to N. Fuson, 7/61
  - Letter to Mrs. McCollum, 7/61
  - Tentative draft of policy statement of the Financial Aid Committee of NCLC, 7/61
  - Mass Meeting Notice, 8/61
  - Tentative form NCLC Financial Aid Committee, 8/61
  - Draft Letter Financial Aid Committee, 8/61
  - Letter to Mrs. W.C. McCollum from Kelly Miller Smith, 8/61
  - Letter to Salynn McCollum from Kelly Miller Smith, 8/61
  - Letter to Wyatt Waller, SCLC from N. Fuson, NCLC Financial Aid Committee, 9/61
  - Letter to Wyatt Walker from N. Fuson, 9/62
  - Letter to Wyatt Walker from N. Fuson Notes: Fiancial Aid Committee, 9/61
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Christian Leadership Counctil (NCLC) 1963
  - General Correspondence
  - Draft memo for Financial Campaign, 3/63
  - Letter to Campaign Committe Members form Inman Otey, 3/63
  - Petition to Mayor Beverly Briley, 3/63
  - Minutes of Meeting: Financial Campaign Notice: NCLC Fight for Freedom Bowling Program, 3/63
  - Letter to Mrs. Fuson from Inman Otey, 3/63
  - Letter to Friend of Freedom from Kelly Miller Smith, 3/63
  - Letter to Citizens of the Nashville Community from Kelly Miller Smith and Andrew White, 3/63
  - Letter from Inman Otey to Friend of Freedom, 4/63
  - Letter Re: March to Washington, 8/63
  - from Kelly Miller Smith, 8/28/63
  - Notice: Freedom Rally Day, Washington, D.C., 8/63
  - Letter to Fellow Student from Ron K. Parker, Grad Student, Vanderbilt University, 11/63
  - Paper: "Toward the Beloved Community: Story of the NCLC"
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Christian Leadership Council (NCLC) 1960-1962
  General Information 1960 Structure of the Nashville Christian Leadership Council
  - Letter to N. Fuson from Kelly Miller Smith and Andrew White, 1/62
  - Newsletter: "News and Notes on National Operation Freedom", 1/62
  - Letter to N. Fuson from Roy J. Williams of Wilson Quick Ad: "H.G. Hill: If you Hire, We will Buy", 2/62
  - Letter to Co-Worker from Matthew Walker, Chair of Financial Campaign, 2/62
  - Letter from Kelly Miller Smith to Friend, 2/62
  - Minutes of Meetings, 2/62
  - Letter from N. Fuson to Matthew Walker, 2/62
  - Letter to Matthew Walker from N. Fuson, 2/62
  - Letter to Matthew Walker from N. Fuson, 2/62
  - Memo to Matthew Walker from N. Fuson, 2/62
  - Letter from Matthew Walker Re: financial campaign, 3/62
  - Program: Operation Open City presents Martin Luther King, Jr. speaking for Civil Rights and Human Dignity, 5/62
  - Letter to Barry Eseher from Kelly Miller Smith, 6/62
  - Letter to Rachel Baker from Kelly Miller Smith 1962 Suggested NCLC Campaign Committee 1962 List of Typical Expenditures, 6/62
  - Ad: "Without Your Help Our Hands are Chained", 1962
- Organizations and Community Activities-NCLC-1962-1963 General Information-File 2 List of Contacts
  - Tentative Draft of letter with rewrite, 2/62
  - Financial Campagin Committee Meeting Financial Campaign Committee, 2/62
  - Letter from J.E. Lowery, Interdenominational Ministers Committee, with copy of Voice of the Movement 2/2 8/62, 3/62
  - Letter to Campaign Members from Matthew Walker Steering Finance Committee, 3/62
  - Letter to Burton and Sue from N. Fuson, 4/63
  - Letter to Friends of Freedom from Inman Otey and Kelly Miller Smith, 4/63
  - Names added to 1962 mail appeal list for NCLC Financial campaign, 5/63
  - Letter to James E. Parkin from N. Fuson with Response, 5/63
- Organizations and Community Activities-NCLC-1964 General Information-File 3
  - Letter to James V. Davis, Mayor of Albany, Georgia from N. Fuson, 2/64
  - Handwritten notes re: Avon Williams and Daniel Williams Copy of Diary of 16 year old girl in jail, 5/64
  - 5/64 Notice of Assembly for NAACP
- Organizations and Community Activities-NCLC-1968 General Information-File 4
  - Letter for support of Poor People's Campaign, Martin Luther King's March on Washington, 4/68
  - Memo/Newsletter to Contributors from SCLC Staff, 4/68
  - Notes/Minutes on Meeting, 7/68
- Organizations and Community Activities-NCLC-1960-1961 Mass Meetings-File 1
  - Mass Meeting Program-Seay-Hubbard Methodist Church, 3/60
  - Mass Meeting Program-Payne Chapel A.M.E. Church, 3/60
  - Nashville 1960: Its Problems and Possibilities: Two-Evening Meeting, 3/60
  - Notice: Martin Luther King to speak 4/20/60 6/60 Mass Meeting Program-Corinthian Baptist Church, 4/60
  - Mass Meeting Program-15th Avenue Church of Christ, 7/60
  - Mass Meeting Agena, 8/60
  - Mass Meeting Program-Kayne Avenue Baptist Church, 12/60
  - Mass Meeting Program-Clark Memorial Methodist Church, 1/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Ebenezer Missionary Baptist Church, 1/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-J. Metz Rollins, Presiding, 3/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-C.T. Vivian, Presiding, 3/61
  - Letter to Friend from Kelly Miller Smith, 4/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Kayne Avenue Baptist Church, 5/61
  - 6/61 Mass Meeting Program-First Baptist Church
- Organizations and Community Activities-NCLC-1961-1963 Mass Meetings-File 2
  - Mass Meeting Program-First Baptist Church, 7/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Sylvan Steet Baptist Church, 7/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-James Lawson, Presiding, 8/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-15th Avenue Church of Christ, 10/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Clark Memorial Methodist Church, 11/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Roger Heights Baptist Church, 11/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Clark Memorial Methodist Church, 11/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Kayne Avenue Baptist Church, 11/61
  - Mass Meeting Program-Mt. Olive Baptist Church, 1/62
  - Regular Meeting Announcement-Clark Memorial Methodist Church and Mass Meeting Announcement-Gay-Lea Christian Church, 2/62
  - Mass Meeting Program-Gay Lea Christian Church, 2/62
  - Notice: Regular Meeting-Clark Memorial Methodist Church and Mass Meeting-Mt. Olive Baptist Church, 3/62
  - Mass Meeting Program-Mt. Zion Primitive Baptist Church, 6/63
- Organizations and Community Activties-NCLC-1960 Sit-In Papers Purposes and Principles of the NCLC
  - Chronological Summary of Nashville Sit-In Demonstration, 3/60
  - Notes of Telephone Call to Dennis Hudson, 3/60
  - Notes of People to Call Suggesting they Attend NCLC Mass Meeting, 3/60
  - Notes of People to Call to form nucleus of the Committee of 100 Agenda, 3/60
  - Nelson Fuson talk at Current Events Luncheon Wesley Foundation concerning Fisk, A & I, Vanderbilt Student Sit- ins, 3/60
  - Letter to Friends from NCLC Citizens Liaison Committee, 6/60
  - Letter to Silvia Saunders from N. Fuson acknowledging receipt of contribution, 7/60
  - Calendar of events, 9/60
  - "Nashville Sit-in Situation" Marion and Nelson Fuson Talk to Bill Fuson's Sociology Class, 11/60
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC)-1955-1956 General Information
  - Community Workshop program, 5/55
  - Summary of the Findings of Twelve Workshop Discusssion Groups, 5/55
  - Workshop Notes, 5/55
  - Summary Report of Nashville's First Workshop on "The Supreme Court Decision and its Meaning for Our Community", 5/55
  - Letter to Nelson and Marian from Gene, 11/55
  - Duke Student Paper: "School's Segregation Policy is 'Barbaric'" 1956 Invitation to become a Charter Member of NCRC, 12/55
  - Community Workshop Group Assignments: "School Integration: How and When?", 2/56
  - Community Workshop program, 2/56
  - Notes taken at workshop, 2/56
  - Memo to Charter Members, 5/56
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC)-1960-1964 General Information Memorial to Mrs. Johnson
  - Discussion Groups, 3/60
  - Report of Nashville 1961: Human Relations Inventory, 4/61
  - Constitution of NCRC, 6/61
  - Memo Re: Study Meeting 3/30-31, 3/63
  - Report of Meeting: "Six Years of Public Desegregation in Nashville and Davidson County" 1964 List of Officers: Executive Committee and Board of Directors, 5/63
  - Minutes of Executive Committee, 6/64
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC)-1962-1965 General Correspondence
  - Letter to M. Fuson from Wallace Westfeldt of NBC, 12/62
  - Memo to Participants in UPUSA Conference on the Southeast from John H. Marion, 2/64
  - Memo: Executive Committee Meeting with Minutes, 3/64
  - Newsletter from M. Fuson 10/64 Letter to Board Members from M. Fuson Notes-handwritten, 4/64
  - Memo to Members of NCRC from M. Fuson, 4/65
  - Notice of Noon Meeting, 4/65
  - Memo to Members of NCRC from M. Fuson 1963- President's Report by Marian Fuson 10/63-5/65 1965, 4/65
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC)-7-10/1968 General Correspondence-James Lanev
  - Memo to Members of Executive Committee with Agenda, 7/68
  - Letter to Church Women Untied from James Laney, 7/68
  - Letter from James Laney, President NCRC to Mayor Beverly Briley, with response, 8/68
  - Letter from James Laney, President NCRC to Dan May, Chair, Metro Action Commission, 8/68
  - Letter to James Laney from Carleen Waller 9/68 Letter to James Laney from Richard H. Bauer, 9/68
  - Letter to James Laney from Loretta Y. Tucker, Secretary to John Dean, 9/68
  - Minutes of Meeting of Executive Committee, 9/68
  - Memo to All Ministers, Nashville Area from James E. Mock, 9/68
  - Report of the Treasurer 5/20/68-10/3/68, 10/68
  - Memo to Board Members Re: Resolution Notes from the Desk of James Laney Handwritten Notes, 10/68
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC)-10-12/68 General Correspondence-James Laney
  - Minutes of Metro Baord of Education, 10/68
  - Letter to Friend form T. Scott Fillebrown of Nashville Religious Society of Friends, 10/68
  - Memo to Members of NCRC Re: Resolution presented to Metro Board of Education, 10/68
  - Recommendation to Metro Board of Education from James Laney, 10/68
  - Letter to James Laney from C. R. Dorrier of Metro Board of Education, 10/68
  - List of Officers of Executive Committees of NCRC, 10/68
  - List of Participants at Meeting, 11/68
  - Notes on Meeting, 11/68
  - Notice of Sadie Wilson Tillman Lectures at Martin College, 11/68
  - Memo to Forum Participants from James Laney, 11/68
  - Meeting Notice: Annual Meeting, Open Forum, Membership Meeting, 11/68
  - Letter to Mr. Bridges from James Laney, 12/68
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC)-1968 Board of Directors Minutes, with Ordinances for Commissions on Human Rights
  - Memo to Board Members from T. A. Smedley Re: Organizational Meeting, 1/68
  - Memo to Board of Directors from T. A. Smedley Re: Policy Committee Report, 3/68
  - Minutes of Board Job Mobilization Support Sheet CEPA Membership Form Model City Code of Fair Practices Henderson Ordinance for the Commission on Human Rights Hopkinsville Ordinance Establishing a Commission on Human Rights Middlesboro, KY Ordinance Establishing a Commission on Human Rights Louisville Ordinance Establishing A Commission on Human Rights Reports of Nominating Committee-NCRC, 6/68
- Organizations and Community Activities-Nashville Community Relations Council (NCRC), 1965-1967 Board of Directors Minutes
  - Memo, 1/65
  - Minutes of Executive Committee, 1/65
  - Letter to Mayor Beverly Briley, 2/65
  - Minutes of Board Meeting 5/65 Minutes of Board Meeting, 4/65
  - Report of Nominating Committee, 5/65
  - Meeting Agena, 5/65
  - Minutes of Board Meeting, 12/66
  - Minutes of Meeting, 1/67
  - Letter to Board Members from Lou Silberman, 2/67